Oh, Shizhen,
对了 世真
you've stayed in the Rong family for several months.
你在容家呆了那么久
Who do you think it can be?
你觉得会是谁
Boss?
七爷
No. This isn't his style.
不 这不是他的行事风格
Rong Dingkun's enemy,
容定坤的仇家
(Right-hand Man Mr. Yang) Yang Xiucheng.
杨秀成
and must hate Rong Dingkun's guts.
肯定将容定坤恨透了
No. It can't be him.
不对 也不是他
Then who was it?
那会是谁呢
I wonder
也不知道
what that old fox Rong Dingkun is going to do
容定坤那老狐狸看到以后
after reading this.
会是什么反应
Will he deny
是矢口否认
or admit it?
还是硬撑着把给它认了下来
You still have my word.
我还是那句话
Give me more time.
你再给我一些时间
I said I wouldn't let you down
我说过不会让你失望
and I'll keep my promise.
就绝不会食言
Could it be him?
会是他吗
Are you with me, Shizhen?
怎么了 世真
Do you have a clue?
是想到什么了吗
I'm as clueless as you.
我现在也不知道情况
Shixun,
哥
you know,
你放心
we aren't the only victims
闻春里受害的
of the Wenchunli Fire.
不止咱们一家人
They just broke the story.
这事不也是第一天吗
We don't know what's next.
局势谁也看不清
Let's wait and see
不如我们耐心等几天
where it goes.
看看后续的情况再说
Sure.
好
It's only a matter of time before our parents find out.
我觉得这个事也瞒不住了
Maybe you should give them a heads-up
不然你跟爹妈先说一声
in case they're caught unprepared.
让他们也好有个心理准备
Got it.
行 我知道了
Shixun,
哥
I'm going out.
我有个事
See you later.
先出去一趟
Go ahead.
好 去吧
Just eat without me.
你们吃饭不用等我了
Sure.
好
- Be careful. - Em.
注意安全啊
This...
这
Fanglin,
姐
is what they said
你说这报纸上说的事
in the newspaper true?
是不是真的呀
I don't know.
我也不知道
When I checked with Jiashang,
我也问大哥了
he didn't say anything
但他什么也没跟我们说
except that we'd better stay at home.
就让我们这阵子在家待着
Don't go anywhere these days.
哪儿也别去
Miss Feng used to live there.
冯先生也是闻春里的
She did say
她之前说过
the fire destroyed their house
她家被火烧了
and injured her father.
她爹也受了伤
I can't imagine
你说
her reaction to this article.
冯先生看完报纸该怎么想啊
Me neither.
我也不知道
But...
这
journalists aren't judges.
就算要定性也得等法院判吧
They have no right to convict anyone.
哪能任凭这报纸上说三道四的
Fanglin,
姐
who was it
你说
that tipped them off?
是谁把这事儿告诉报社的
Look.
你看
(Right-hand Man Mr. Yang) Here it says "Mr. Yang".
这上面写的杨某
Yang Xiucheng?
会不会是秀成哥
I can't believe
居然是他们家人干的
the Rongs did it!
这件事居然是他们家人干的
If our neighbors find out
世真在他们家工作了这么久
Shizhen worked for them,
这件事如果让街坊邻居们知道了
that will be a disaster!
那怎么得了啊
Mother...
妈
It's too soon to tell
这件事
how this is going to turn out.
不知道会弄成什么样子
Luckily,
好在
Shizhen got out in time.
世真已经从容家辞职了
My biggest fear
我最担心的
is those rumors.
是外面的那些胡乱传言
Father, Mother,
爹 妈
I'm still in touch with Mr. Zhang's second son.
我呀跟张家的老二还有联系
I'll talk to him later
我准备这两天去跟他碰个头
and figure out
商议一下
a solution.
该怎么解决这件事
I'll get back
街坊邻居们的公道
what they owe us and our neighbors.
我一定要给他们讨回来
Shixun,
世勋哪
listen,
你听妈话
do not join the crowd
如果这个邻居们去闹事
to go after the Rongs, you hear me?
你千万别凑过去 你听见没有
Mother.
妈
Our family has barely settled down.
我们这个家刚刚稳定下来
We can't afford any more risks.
可不行 你可别再折腾了
Rong Dingkun is rich and powerful.
容定坤他有权有势
Fighting against him
万一为了这件事情
could cost you
你再把工作丢了
your job!
那可怎么得了啊
Don't forget your sister
还有你妹妹
was his children's governess.
她在容家工作了这么久
Once she's dragged into this mess,
女孩子的名声是很重要的
her reputation will be ruined
如果这件事情牵连到她
or...
这
or worse, her life!
这不是害了她吗
That's a valid concern.
你妈妈说得对
Right now,
现在
we don't know if he did it
这一切还只是传闻
without evidence.
没有任何真凭实据
And
况且
Rong Dingkun hasn't said anything.
容定坤又没有承认
Things could go either way.
一切都不好说
Sound out
你去看看
our old neighbors on their attitudes.
那些老街坊们是什么态度
But no way
但要容定坤认
will Rong Dingkun admit to anything.
他怎么可能会认嘛
So,
今天你来找我
what brings you here?
是有什么事情吗
It's nothing serious.
打扰七爷了
I hate to bother you,
也不是什么大事
but...
我就是
I'm baffled.
有些没头绪
By this news article?
如果你要问的是这件事的话
What I can tell you is
我可以告诉你
I didn't do it.
不是我做的
I thought so.
果然不是七爷做的
You did?
你猜到了
There's always a purpose
七爷您做任何事情
for everything you do.
都会有明确的目的
Making the Wenchunli Fire public
公开闻春里这件事
would tarnish Rong Dingkun's image
确实可以抹黑容定坤
and hit the stocks of his company.
让容家的股票跌一番
Were it you,
但如果是您做的话
you'd attack him from all angles
一定会配合上其他行动一起
to take him down once and for all.
力求一鼓作气干掉容定坤
But now isn't the time
但这个时候发起全面攻击
for an all-out attack.
时机并不成熟
Besides,
况且
had you had such a plan,
如果您要做这件事情的话
you wouldn't have left me out of the loop.
没有理由不告知我
You have a clear
思维缜密
and analytical mind
滴水不漏
and
而且
you know me all too well.
你越来越了解我了
Thanks.
七爷过奖了
It was
这件事情
your lovey-dovey suitor, Rong Jiashang,
是你家那个痴情的容大少
who sacrificed his family
为了爱
for love.
大义灭亲
You did well, Shizhen.
世真 你做得很好
Let's see what will happen to you two.
让我来猜一猜你们俩的结局吧
You can elope.
私奔
But the real question is
但是你有没有想过
will Rong Jiashang go with you?
容嘉上愿不愿意跟你私奔
And
以及
will you change your mind
到一半的时候
halfway?
你会不会改变主意
If you do, come back anytime.
你要是中途反悔了 回来找我
I'll take care of you.
我定会好生安置你
There are plenty of men
毕竟这个世上
out there,
男人多了去了
but a talent like you
但我们聪明的小世真
is one of a kind.
却只有一个
I'm flattered.
七爷说笑了
Uncle,
表姨父
it wasn't me.
这事不是我做的
I'd never betray you!
我绝无可能背叛您
Ruining your image
纵使我要毁掉您的清名
would do me no good.
于我杨秀成有什么好处
Everyone in the city knows
现在整个上海滩的人都知道
I'm your little stooge,
我是您的走狗
your fixer.
我要到处替您杀人放火
A senior clansman
我今日还接到族里长辈的电话
was misled by the paper
那边不分青红皂白
and yelled at me on the phone earlier,
把我骂得狗血喷头
threatening to expel me.
说要把我逐出族里
My family still depends on our clan.
我的家人还在靠族里人照顾
I wouldn't stab you in the back
就算我要背叛您
even for their sake.
我不至于弃我的家人于不顾吧
If I sink,
我要是不好过
you'll sink deeper.
你会更不好过
Uncle,
姨父
I'll get to the bottom of this
我一定会彻查此事
and find whoever did it.
一定把这个人给找出来
Who do you think
那你说说看
is behind everything?
这件事会是谁干的呀
It could be
我怀疑
Miss Feng who just left.
是刚刚辞职的冯先生
I'm listening.
接着说
It couldn't be a coincidence
天底下没有那么巧的事情
that she came to work for us
他们家被我们放火烧了
right after we burned down her house.
她就来容家做家庭教师
Ever since she arrived,
她来我们容家这几个月来
so many unexpected things
大事小事不断
have happened.
从来没有消停过
None of them is linked to her,
虽说都牵扯不到她身上
but she had the run of the house
但是她在容家来去自如
and was on good terms with the servants.
跟下人又混得熟
Who knows how much she's found about us?
谁知道她暗地里打探了多少秘密
And the timing is most suspicious
最巧的是
that this scandal was published
她这前脚刚刚辞职
right after she quit.
后脚丑闻就曝出来了
So all in all,
说来说去
it's a woman's fault?
都是女人的错呗
Xiucheng,
杨表哥
you're an educated college graduate.
你也是接受过新思潮的大学生
Why are you blaming everything on women
怎么还是继承了把黑锅
like the old school?
随便推给女人的好习惯呢
Jiashang,
嘉上
I know you like her,
我知道你喜欢她
but don't let emotions cloud your judgment
但不能因为这个你就如此武断
and cover for her.
一味地替她辩驳
I do like her,
我是喜欢她
but it was you and Mrs. Rong
但是当初把她招进来的
who hired her in the first place.
是你和太太
Had you known she couldn't be trusted,
她的底细你们不是没有查清楚
why would you have let her in
那为什么还要把她招进来
to teach us?
当家庭教师
That makes me question
我倒要问问你
your intention!
你到底是什么用意
We hired her
当初招她进来
because we suspected her motives
就是因为她动机可疑
and let her in to watch her closely.
招她进来就是为了盯住她
You're a terrible liar!
你说的这番话小孩子都不信
You're trying to
你不就是想说
pin the blame on her
我们家最近发生的事情
for all that's happened, aren't you?
都是冯先生背后搞鬼吗
Then let me ask you this.
那我倒要问问你
She might've
孙少清逃跑
talked Sun Shaoqing into escaping.
可以说是冯世真怂恿的
Yes.
没关系
But what about Zhihui?
但是知惠表姐呢
What did she have anything to do
知惠表姐的事情
with her action?
跟她又有什么关系
We checked her
无论是把她招进来之前
over and over
还是聘用她的几个月
before and after she was hired.
你我都反复调查过了
We had her tailed
暗中也派人盯梢了
and gave her a polygraph test
最后还用上了测谎仪
which she passed.
不是什么都没有发现吗
That article includes details
现在在报道上写的
such as the shell company.
连皮包公司的事情都清清楚楚
I don't believe a governess like her
我就不信她一个小老师
could dig that deep.
能有这么大的能耐
Xiucheng,
表哥
I trust that you didn't leak anything,
我相信你没有泄密
but you can't make her a scapegoat
但是你不能找不到泄密的人
before finding the real leaker.
就随便拉一个人来顶包
Enough!
好了
Stop the blame game.
现在说这些都没有意义
What we need is a solution.
当务之急是要看看怎么解决
We've become the talk of the town.
现在这事闹得满城风雨
Reporters are outside our house.
记者把容家都围住了
We can't even go out.
容家的人连门都出不去
Other than that,
不仅如此
victims of the fire
闻春里的那帮灾民
are coming after us.
还想就着此事闹事呢
What can
一帮平头百姓
those peasants do?
还怕他们闹事吗
They don't know
真是太岁头上动土
who they're messing with.
活腻歪了
So...
表姨父的意思是
We've hired tons of musclemen
我们容家手下那么多打手
to do their job.
干什么吃的
Keep an eye on those people.
你派人盯紧闻春里
Take care of all the troublemakers.
谁敢闹事就往死里打
Break them or kill them.
打不死
And I need you
至于那个始作俑者
to track down the mastermind, Xiucheng.
你得好好查一查 秀成
I need to know who that enemy is.
看看是谁跟我容定坤作对啊
Consider it done.
姨父放心
I'll bring that guy to you
就算掘地三尺
at all costs.
我也要把这个人给挖出来
What about those reporters?
那帮记者如何处理
Jiashang,
嘉上
you and Yunchi are friends.
你跟云驰熟
Tell him
你去跟他说一说
to say someone else did it,
拉出个替罪羊来
not us.
说这事跟容家没关系
We need the media to be on our side.
好好打点一下
Violence
爹这么做
is one way to vent out your anger,
的确能出一口恶气
but I don't think
但是儿子始终认为
it's the best way.
有些不妥
Why?
怎么不妥呀
The one behind is fanning the flame.
既然这件事情背后有人怂恿
There's no way to put it out quietly.
那不闹是不可能的
Now that
现在所有事情的风头
all the eyes are on us,
都集中在我们容家
if anything happens to those victims,
闻春里那帮人要是出了什么事情
we'll be the first to blame.
外界肯定会联系到我们家
And things will get worse.
事情只会越闹越大
Whatever we say won't matter anymore.
到时候我们有嘴也说不清楚
The suspect is still out there
更何况现在背后的人还没查出来
in the dark
我们在明
while we remain an open target.
对方在暗
The longer this mess drags on,
这件事情越拖
the bigger it grows
只会闹得越大
and the worse we look.
对我们容家越是不利
Father,
爹
the priority
我认为当务之急
is to dissociate ourselves
我们应该以最快的速度
from this matter as soon as possible.
让容家和这件事情撇清关系
You have a point.
你说得确实有道理
But how?
那你说说看
What should we do?
该怎么解决啊
Father,
爹
I'll handle it
您若是放心的话
if you trust me.
这件事情交给我来办
It'll blow over
我保证在三天之内
in three days,
把这件事情平息下去
but
只不过
at a cost.
需要花点钱罢了
Money is never a problem.
钱不是问题
Alright.
好
Just get it done.
这件事情就交给你去处理
You may leave. I'm tired.
你们去吧 我累了
Yes.
是
Did Boss say anything?
七爷没说什么吧
I read the paper
报纸我都看了
and I was worried about you.
我还挺担心你的
I'm fine.
我没事
You know who did it?
那你知道这事是谁做的吗
It was Rong Jiashang.
是容嘉上
Shizhen,
世真
isn't this
你努力了这么久
what you've been working so hard for?
不就是为了这个吗
Do you think
那你觉得
he'll coarse his father into pleading guilty for you?
他会为了你逼他爹认罪吗
I'm not sure.
我不知道
Shizhen,
世真
you do have
你对他
expectations in your relationship.
终究还是有期待的
Baoli.
宝丽
It's getting harder and harder
我最近越来越分不清楚
to tell how I feel about him.
我对他到底是真还是假
Look,
我看
you're already in love with him.
你可能是真的爱上他了
Rong Jiashang belongs to the sky.
容嘉上是一个热爱蓝天
His dream is to be a pilot.
憧憬飞翔的人
If you were right,
如果我真的爱上他了
I'd be seeing the man I love
我就眼睁睁地看着他
rolling into the deep
一步步走向深渊
without doing anything
不但不去制止
and I even...
甚至我还
Alright, alright.
好了好了
Calm down. Let it go.
不想了 不想了
Steamed buns!
馒头啊
- I'm going to play with my friends. - Hot steamed buns!
我去玩会儿
- Sure. Don't run around. - Take your time, Miss.
别跑远啊
Yes.
这都是新鲜的
Shixun,
哥
aren't you going to work?
今天没上班啊
I'm having a day off.
我今天轮休
Shizhen,
对了世真
let's go to a meeting.
一会儿啊你跟我去个集会
What meeting?
什么集会
Where is he?
怎么还没来
Got it?
记住了吗
Shixun.
世勋
Welcome.
来了
Hello.
师兄
Good to have you here.
这次你能来真是太好了
Let me introduce to you,
介绍一下
my sister, Shizhen.
这是家妹 世真
Shizhen,
世真
meet Editor Zhang of People's Weekly.
这是先民周报的张主编
We went to the same college.
也是我大学时候的师兄
Nice to meet you.
你好
Have a seat.
两位快请坐吧
- Thanks. - Sure.
好
Go ahead.
坐
Let's get started.
来 我们来开会
Let's go. Take a seat.
来
Guys,
各位
Dr. Feng and I
冯医生
have discussed this matter
之前和我就闻春里的事
more than once.
已经谈了好几次了
We don't know
虽然不知道
who's using the media against Rong Dingkun,
是容定坤的哪个仇家
but it plays right into our hands.
但是也算是帮了我们一个大忙
- That's right. - Agreed.
是啊 是啊就是
The problem is
只是
it's difficult
事情进展到这一步
to push forward
想要再进一步
from where we are now.
就难了
That's true.
是啊
The evidence is lacking
终究是证据不充足
and Rong Dingkun is too powerful.
而容定坤的势力实在是太强大了
The government is knee-deep in the war
政府现在忙着打仗
and corruption.
法纪败坏
No one is there
谁又有工夫
to uphold justice.
来主持这个公道呢
Then why are we here?
那你今天叫我们来这儿做什么
We can't do anything
告又告不了他
other than condemn him in the paper.
只能在报纸上骂他几句
That won't hurt him at all.
他容定坤还怕被骂吗
- Don't you agree? - Yes.
对不对
- Right. - That's true.
对啊 对啊
He'll still be a big boss,
到最后他继续做他的大老板
raking in dirty money
赚他的黑心钱
while we remain down and out
咱们不还是拖着个残腿
with broken legs.
回去喝西北风吗
Am I right?
大家说是不是
- Yes. - That's right.
就是啊
or there might be direr consequences.
怕会引来更大的祸害啊
- Absolutely! - Of course.
是啊
We aren't the snitch.
这告密的不是我们
What if Rong Dingkun thinks we are
容家要是怀疑我们
and gets back at us?
反过来报复我们怎么办
- Yes. - Then what?
对
He'll crush us!
我们这不是以卵击石吗这
Yes. We aren't his match.
是啊 这咱可得罪不起
Enough!
各位
Guys,
各位街坊
have you forgotten
难道大家是忘了
about all our suffering
之前发生在我们身上的不幸
and pain?
和灾难了吗
How could we?
那能忘啊
Right.
是
We weren't rich
我们之前都不算什么富贵人家
but we were doing fine.
但至少衣食无忧吧
- But - Yes.
可就是因为
that sudden fire
那一场突如其来的大火
changed everything.
我们的一切全变了
Mr. Li,
李大哥
you were blinded by the smoke
您的双眼被烟熏瞎了
and could no longer teach.
自此再也无法教书
Ms. Wang,
王嫂子
your son and daughter
您的儿子女儿可是双双
were both killed in it.
葬身于大火之中啊
Mr. Huang,
还有黄大哥
after the beam broke your leg,
您的腿被横梁砸断了
you lost your job
自此工作丢了
and
就连嫂子也
your wife.
也离你而去了
I'm not bringing this up
我说这些事情
to reopen your old wounds
不是想揭开旧伤疤
and upset you,
惹大家不开心
but to remind you
而是我们本可以
how much that fire took from us.
非常美好地生活下去
It took our family, our life
就因为一场大火把我们的一切
and everything we had.
都变了 都毁了
Don't you want revenge?
各位难道不气愤吗
Don't you hold a grudge?
不怨恨吗
Or,
还是说
would you put it behind,
我们就选择遗忘
let it go
得过且过
and move on with your life?
继续我们新的生活了
Uh...
这 这
Rong Dingkun must pay for what he did!
当然不能就这么放过他
I'm all alone.
我孤家寡人一个
I could put my life on the line
就算拼了这条命
to get revenge on him.
去找容定坤报仇
No one else would get hurt.
也就死我一个人
But you're different.
可在场的街坊邻居
You all have a family.
你们都上有老 下有小
- Shixun, - That's right.
冯兄弟
you have parents and a sister.
你有高堂还有妹妹
I don't think
我想
you'll risk your life
你也不敢跟容定坤
to battle Rong Dingkun, right?
硬拼吧
Don't you think so?
大家说是不是
- Yes. - Right.
是啊
Just try to be understanding.
都相互理解吧
We hate his guts,
不是不恨
but we can't act on impulse.
可总得有个法子啊
We're either old or disabled.
这大家老的老 残的残
If it were just us,
要真是光棍啊
we'd do anything
舍得一身剐
to destroy that man
敢把皇帝拉下马
because we had nothing to lose.
跟那容定坤拼了
- Yes! - Of course!
对 对
- But in reality, - Battle it out!
可是现在
we... We're the pillar of our family.
这 偏偏大伙家里有老有小
So...
这
That's why
所以啊
Dr. Feng invited me over.
冯医生才叫我过来
If we can't take legal action
既然我们通过法律手段
against Rong Dingkun,
没有办法实现正义
the alternative
那么
is to bring him to his knees
我们就借用舆论之手
with public opinion.
让容定坤屈服
Will that work?
舆论管用吗
Yes. Will it succeed?
就是 管用吗
No way.
没用 没用
Public opinion?
管用吗
- Hear me out. - That's right.
大家听我说啊
With
如今
the scandal trending
趁着舆论的热度
and the evidence we have,
再加上我们手上现有的证据
there's enough leverage for negotiations.
我们足够可以和容家谈判了
Don't you agree?
对不对啊
Am I right?
对不对
Sounds about right, but...
好像有点道理 不过
That's not bad, but...
是个办法 但是
Yes. That's right.
对对对
They must pay for our losses.
让容家赔钱
We can't sit and do nothing.
不能就这么算了
I lost three family members!
我家可是死了三个人哪
Rong Dingkun must kneel
要让容定坤给死的人
and apologize to the deceased.
磕头谢罪
- That's right! Kneel and apologize! - Yes! Kneel and apologize!
对对对 磕头谢罪
- Let's go! - Yes! He must do that!
走
Let's go to his house
咱们现在就去容家
to make him pay for what he did!
让容定坤给咱们一个说法
- Let's go!
走
- Wait! Calm down! - Guys, guys!
大哥 大哥
You can't show up at his door
大家不能就这么去啊
without a negotiation plan
我们得先有个谈判的计划
and a negotiator.
还得推选出来一个谈判的代表啊
Negotiation?
谈判
Negotiator?
谈判代表
I got this. Sit back.
没事的 你先坐吧
I've done
谈判
negotiations before.
我有经验
I can do it.
我去谈判
You can't even drive a bargain,
你买菜都不会砍价
let alone negation.
懂什么谈判呢
Look,
我看
I'm the one for the job.
还是我去的为好啊
Mr. Liu,
刘老哥
you owe more money than us.
我们之中你欠债最多
You're the neediest.
也最缺钱
What if
可别到时侯
Rong Dingkun pays you
得了容定坤的好处
What's that supposed to mean?
你这是什么话呀
- You don't trust me? - Just ask others.
你不能这么怀疑我吧你
Am I right?
你们说是不是
I'm sorry.
让师兄笑话了
They weren't
这些街坊
like this.
以前不是这样的
can turn people into what they aren't.
会彻底地改变一个人的
The poorer they get,
生活陷入困境
the greedier they become.
就会让人变得更加近利
That's human nature.
这也是
- You got me wrong. - He's right.
本能所使
It's for everyone's sake!
这不是为大家好吗 你看看
- I'd never do that! - Stop, all of you!
好了好了好了
You can't read or write
你们都是粗人
but Dr. Feng has studied abroad.
冯医生是留过洋回来的
He should be our negotiator.
我看还是让他去做代表吧
Foreign education
留洋回来怎么了
doesn't make him better than us!
留洋就比我们高一等吗
Don't forget
况且
his sister used to teach
他妹妹还不是给容家
Rong Dingkun's children.
当家庭教师呢吗
How can you be sure
你怎么知道
that they aren't on the same side?
他们两家不会通气了呢
Yes.
是啊
She's having an affair
冯小姐好像和容家大少爷
with his eldest son.
不清白呢
What if she takes our money
别到时候贪了我们赔偿银子
to pay for her dowries?
给她做了嫁妆
Ma'am,
姨
that's ridiculous.
您这话可就不对了
My sister has
我家妹子和容家
nothing to do with the Rongs.
可没有半点关系了
How are we supposed to trust you?
你说没有就没有
Your sister did work for them,
你家妹子在容家做家庭教师
didn't she?
总是事实吧
Stop denying it!
现在不认了
You can't bend the truth.
真假全凭你们一张嘴呀
Knock it off!
说的什么话呀
Dr. Feng
冯医生难道不是
is one of us, isn't he?
我们一条船上的人吗
He's trying to help us,
人家好心地张罗
yet you're divided on your own agenda
你们这些人各自有私心内斗不断
and speaking ill of his sister.
还把人家好心拉下水了
You seemed to be all nice and kind
往日做街坊邻居的时候
before anything happened,
一个个人模人样的
but that fire
现在一把火
has burned out your true colors.
把你们烧出原形了
We... We didn't mean to hurt anyone.
这 倒也不是这个意思
Who are they?
这什么人来了
Why are they here?
这是干吗呀
You're right.
大叔说得对
Solidarity is the foundation of success.
同仇敌忾乃是成事基础
A divided group
可不能还没出门
can't get anything done.
就自乱阵脚
Rong Jiashang!
容嘉上
How did you find us?
你怎么找到这里来了
Is he
就是那个
Rong Dingkun's son?
容定坤的儿子吗
How dare you show up!
容家的人也敢来
- We were about to go to your place! - Yes!
我们正要找你算账
And here you are!
你倒自己送上门来了
He can't leave
今天容家
until he gives us
要是不给咱们一个说法
- what we need! - Yes!
咱们就不让他们出去
- He can't go! - We can't let him go!
不能走
We demand an explanation!
一定要给我们一个说法
What are you doing?
干什么啊你们
What is this?
你们要干什么
We're here to talk.
我们是来商谈的
Don't scare them.
别吓到他们
Rumor has it
最近一直有传言
that my father sent people
说当初闻春里的大火
to set Wenchunli on fire
是我爹派人做下的
to obtain the land.
为的就是收下那块地
I'm here
关于这件事情呢
to explain everything to you.
我今天过来和大家解释一下
Back then,
我爹当初
he did have his eyes on the land
的确是想收下闻春里那块地
but gave it up
可是因为价格居高不下
for its high cost.
一早就放弃了
Someone else burned it
实际火烧闻春里的人
and gave it to my father
欠下我爹巨债
to pay off his huge debts.
用闻春里低了债
So,
所以此事
my father didn't do it.
并不是我爹所为
- Liar! - Yes!
谁信哪 对呀
- Why should we believe you? - Right.
你说不是就不是啊
- Your father did it! - Stop twisting the facts!
真的假的
Well,
当然了
given my father's experience,
家父经商多年
I'd be lying if I said
若是说没有怀疑过这块地
he didn't suspect a thing.
那也是骗人的
He took that land
是家父贪利
without asking too much
没有深究
for profits,
便收下了闻春里
which got him into trouble now.
所以才吃下了这个口舌官司
I believe
我想
he's learned from his mistake.
他从中也得到了教训
I apologize
我今日听闻
for barging into
诸位街坊在此聚会
your meeting,
容某不请自来
but I meant to get things straight
便是想把此事解释清楚
and
另外
offer you
也和大家谈谈
compensation.
赔偿事宜
- Compensation? - What?
赔偿
- Will they pay us? - Compensation?
那么好心
- Really? - Is that true?
要赔偿啊
Really?
真的假的啊
Mr. Rong Jiashang,
容大少爷
nice story.
您可真会编故事啊
You could make a career
您这样不去写小说
out of it.
实在可惜了
If it's true that the one in debt
如若真如您所说
to your father did it,
那么那位欠容家钱的人
get him here
可否请他过来
to corroborate your statement.
为您的话作证呢
- Yes! That's right! - Get him here.
是啊 是啊
- Where is he? - Let him testify.
请过来嘛
- Too bad, - Yes.
很抱歉
he also owed the Green Gang
那个人后来又欠了青帮的债
who killed him six months ago.
在半年前已经被打死了
- What? - A dead man can't talk.
说了嘛 这这
I've submitted all the necessary files,
相关的文件
documents and evidence
资料 罪证
to the police.
我都已经提交了警察局
If you still have doubts,
诸位街坊若是不信
check with them yourselves.
可以亲自去警察局里查问
We...
我们
Basically,
那你的意思
no one is there to confirm your story.
就是死无对证了
You could say that,
若真要这么说
I guess.
也的确如此
How are we supposed to believe
那我们要怎么相信
your father is innocent?
你们家是无辜的
You can't prove
可是你们也没有证据
he's guilty, either.
能证明此事就是家父所为
If your father didn't do it,
如果不是你们家做的
why are you here?
那你今天来这儿做什么呢
Why would he come if they're innocent?
跟他家没关系 他来干吗呀
What's he here for?
要不没事来干什么呀
They're guilty.
就是心虚
Guys,
诸位
my father didn't arrange that fire.
此事确实不是家父所为
But he did
但是也因为家父当初逼债
push the arsonist too hard
让对方铤而走险
who went to extremes.
从而酿下了大祸
We're sorry for your loss
容家素来宽厚
and my father and I have decided
我同家父商议后决定
to make up for it.
我们也会承担责任
How hypocritical!
真是虚伪
The killer is playing nice
杀人放火的是你们
to the bereaved.
现在行善积德装好人的又是你们
Rong Jiashang,
容嘉上
you're as despicable as your father.
你跟你爹还真是如出一辙啊
Miss Feng...
先生
Stop!
站住
I know
我知道
words alone
无论现在说什么
can't comfort you.
都没有办法平息大家心里的愤怒
Bring it in.
抬上来
What is it?
什么东西
Gold bars!
金条
For real?
真的呀
These gold bars.
这些金条
Is it real gold?
真的假的
They are labeled
上面都打有标码
and can be sold anytime.
大家可以随时兑换
One gold bar equals
一根金条的市值
approximately 300 silver dollars.
大约是三百块大洋
- 300? - That much?
三百块大洋啊
You'll get one once you sign
只要你们签下谅解书协议
the Statement of Understanding.
就可以领取一条
The disabled ones
家中若是有残疾
or those who lost their friends or family
或者亲友病故
will get one more
有邻居作证
once confirmed by their neighbors.
可以再多加一条
I promise
我们容家
that we'll take responsibility.
一定会承担自己的责任
Our offer is fair and reasonable
明码标价
to everyone.
童叟无欺
Rong Jiashang
这个容公子
is good.
可真是有些手段哪
You can put a price on lost property,
财产损失可以赔
but life?
但人命呢
One life
难道一根金条
for one gold bar?
就能换回一条人命吗
But now,
可现在
the Rongs aren't admitting to arson
容家并不认放火的事
or murder.
自然也不会认人命的事
They're
说白了
buying off the victims
就是拿钱堵口
to make this thing go away.
想把这事糊弄过去
Or
要不然
why sign the Statement of Understanding?
签什么谅解书啊
So,
所以说
young as Rong Jiashang seems,
他看起来年纪轻轻
he's sophisticated.
但是却很精明
Obviously,
我想
your neighbors
闻春里的街坊们
want revenge
何尝不知道这个道理
but the odds are against us.
只是胜算太小
Justice
公道
is no more useful than gold.
还不如真金白银来得划算
Are we letting Rong Dingkun go?
难道就这样放过容定坤吗
Miss Feng,
我的想法
I'm on your side,
和冯小姐一样的
but
但是
look at them.
你们看看这些人
They care more
他们大多
about their benefit.
都还想着衣食
They're counting on
对于他们来说
Rong Dingkun's money
比起让容定坤偿命
to improve their life
还不如让他们拿着赔偿金
instead of bringing him to justice.
改善生活
You and your brother
冯小姐和令兄
won't give up
都是意志坚定
until justice is served,
不折不挠的人
but all they want
可是他们
is food and clothes.
只求衣食无忧
We need to survive.
我们也得活呀
I have a big family.
我上有老下有小
I'm in desperate need of money.
这钱我还真的需要
I'll sign it.
我签
300 silver dollars
三百块大洋啊
is enough to buy a small house
不仅能买套小房子
and put us
今年
through this year.
也能过个好年了
The Rongs are generous.
这容家还真是爽快
We don't have to put up a fight.
如今我们不用吵不用闹
All we need is to sign that paper.
只需要签字罢了
I'll do it.
我签
Me too.
我也去
Yes, just sign it.
就是啊
Better stay away from trouble.
多一事不如少一事
Sign it and let it go.
咱们就息事宁人吧
Yes. You're right.
对啊 对对对
Let's sign it
咱们就跟着孙奶奶
with Ms. Sun.
一起去签了算了
I'll sign it, too.
我也要签了
- Come here. - Don't push.
别挤
It'll soon be your turn.
一会儿就轮到你们了
One at a time.
一个一个来
He's got it!
真给呢
- Yes! - Sign it.
真给啊 签签签
Look!
你看
Shizhen!
世真
Shixun,
世勋
let her go.
没事
Your sister
你妹妹
knows what she's doing.
是个有主意的人
No one died in our family,
我们冯家没死人
but we lost a big house
但是房子特别大
and a two-door wide store.
还有两个门的铺面
Mr. Rong Jiashang,
容大少
what's all that worth?
你看这个账该怎么算
Given your condition,
冯家情况特殊
your compensation should be doubled.
理应给双倍的金条
Your family is powerful and well-connected.
容家权势在握 人脉通达
It's generous of you
今天肯拿金条来买我们闭嘴
to silence us with gold bars.
还真是下了血本了
As your governess,
我这个当先生的
I should support you.
怎么能不捧我学生的场呢
Shixun,
哥
take them.
收着
Shizhen,
世真
are you out of your mind?
你 你疯了
Miss Feng!
先生
Shizhen!
世真
Now what?
怎么
You want your money back?
容大少爷这是反悔了吗
Miss Feng,
先生
I'm doing my best to make it up to you
我已经在尽全力补救了
and I want everyone to be happy,
我也想做到尽善尽美
but I...
但是我真的已经
I'd take your word for it
如果你是毫不知情
if you didn't know the truth,
我相信你是在尽力补救
but you do know everything.
但你明明什么都知道
Rong Jiashang,
容嘉上
I'm so disappointed in you.
你太让我失望了
I know you still hold a grudge,
我知道你心里怨我
but this is the best I can do.
但是这是我能想到最好的办法了
If your enemy shamed you with money,
如果你现在被仇人用钱打了脸
would you still be nice to him?
你还会对他笑脸相迎吗
Miss Feng,
先生
I'll take care of those
闻春里放火的那几个人
who set the fire.
我都会处理掉
Because you can't do anything
发号施令的人动不了
to the one who gave them the order.
只能去处置几个狗腿子
Rong Jiashang,
容嘉上
if we
如果我们两个人
swap places,
现在互换一下位置
you'll understand
你就知道
how I feel.
我现在心里是什么感受了
If my father burned your house
如果是我爹烧了你们家
and I came to hand out money
我现在把钱甩在你脸上
to shut you up,
还让你别抱怨
hoping you'd still be with me,
最好还能和我谈情说爱
would you
你扪心自问
agree to that?
你能做到吗
Shizhen,
世真
do I have to cut all ties with my family
难道只有我不做容家人
to get a chance with you?
我们才有一丝机会吗
But you won't.
但是你不会的
It's not that
这个事情
you can't,
倒不是你不能
but I don't deserve such sacrifice.
而是我还不值得你这么做
Come in.
进来
Mr. Rong,
容老板
a Miss Hashimoto is here.
有一位桥本小姐来访
Miss Hashimoto,
桥本小姐
what can I do for you?
我有什么可以帮你的
I wouldn't dare trouble you.
容伯伯客气了
I'm here for a sensitive matter
这本应该是容家的家事
involving your family.
我这个外人
It's not my place to interfere,
不应该掺和
but I care about Jiashang.
但也因为我对嘉上
He's a victim of deception.
我不想嘉上再继续被蒙蔽了
I don't want him
不想到时候
to get hurt
他伤了心
or you suffer any losses.
您伤了财
You're my son's friend
你和嘉上是朋友
which makes you sort of a family.
在我眼中你就像是亲侄女一般
You can tell me
所以有什么话
anything.
大可直说
Two weeks ago,
半个月前
when Taiji and I went to Hangzhou for visiting,
我和弟弟去杭州拜访远亲
we accidentally ran into
在酒店不小心碰到了
Miss Du and her friend in the hotel
杜小姐和她的朋友
and snapped this photo.
就顺手拍了这张照片
Mr. Rong,
但容伯伯
don't get me wrong.
您千万不要误会
I didn't do it out of jealousy
我绝对不是出于嫉妒
or mean to go between them.
也不是想要破坏什么
Taiji asked me to send it to you anonymously,
弟弟也劝我寄封匿名信就算了
but after careful consideration,
但我觉得
I'd rather talk to you openly
还是要公开跟您说一说
than gossip behind your back.
不要做背后嚼舌根的小人
Jiashang can't see this photo.
这照片确实不能让嘉上看到
Thank you
不过还是要感谢桥本小姐
for being so sweet and thoughtful.
细心体贴啊
No need.
容伯伯见外了
Our two families are bonded.
我们两家关系非同一般
It's the least
这点小事
we should do.
不足挂齿
I know you and Jiashang are friends,
我只是听嘉上说你们是朋友
but you're
但是真没想到
more intelligent than I thought.
桥本小姐是如此地聪慧机敏
I'm impressed.
让我印象深刻呀
Alright.
好了
What else?
不绕弯子了
Get it all out.
还有什么话
I'm listening.
不必对我隐瞒
Fine. I'll be straight.
那我就直说了
To be honest,
说句心里话
I still love Jiashang
我对嘉上的感情
as much as I did before.
其实一直都没有变过
I was heartbroken
他生日那天
seeing him getting engaged
当我看到他订婚的时候
on his birthday.
我心都碎了
When I
后来
found out about his fiance's affair,
又发现他未婚妻不忠
I felt enraged and sorry for him.
我更是替他感到愤怒难过
In my eyes,
嘉上在我心里
no one is better than him.
一直都是天底下最好的男人
If I were his wife,
如果我是他的妻子
I'd spend the rest of my life
我一定会奉献出我的一生
making him happy.
让他幸福快乐
All I need
只是不知道
is a chance.
还有没有这样的福气
It takes
一个女孩子
a lot of courage
把话说到这份上
to pour your heart out like that.
不容易啊
I apologize
我只是一个不懂事的晚辈
if I cross the line.
还请容伯伯多多包涵
So,
那么
why should I
给我一个理由
help you?
我为什么要帮你啊
Du Lanxin is cheating on your son.
杜兰馨既然不守妇道
You can cancel their engagement
您大可以拿着证据去退婚
without losing anything
杜家理亏
once you show that photo to the Dus.
您自然不会损失什么
After that,
而我
you can have me
我会带着金麒麟
as well as the Gold Kylin.
嫁到府上
Mr. Rong, I understand you want
我知道容伯伯您想要这金麒麟
that Gold Kylin and you want it now,
而且要得着急
but my father
而这东西
cherishes it.
只有家父视若珍宝
If
如果
Jiashang takes me back,
我能跟嘉上再续前缘
I promise that I'll hand it
我一定会拿着金麒麟
to you on a plate.
亲自送到您手中
And in terms of our business,
况且在商言商
we're only sharing with you
桥本家北方的航线
one shipping route in the north.
其实也只拿出了一条与您共享
Taiji and I believe
而我和弟弟都觉得
we can deepen
我们两家的合作
our cooperation.
可以再紧密些
Mr. Rong,
容伯伯
trust me.
您相信我
Only I can
只有我
merge our two families into one.
才可以让容家和桥本家融为一体
Taiji
我这个弟弟
is nothing but a hedonist.
一生理想不过吃喝玩乐
Once he's in charge,
等到他继承了桥本家
I'll have to manage everything for him.
最后还是得由我来管理
If Jiashang and I get married,
如果我嫁到容家
what's mine
我管理
will also be yours,
和容家管理
am I right?
又有什么区别呢
That way,
这样一来岂不是
the Hashimotos' property will go to us.
容家吞并了桥本家
Is that what you want?
你甘心吗
As Jiashang's wife,
我如果嫁给了嘉上
I'm one of you, of course.
我自然就是容家人了
Whatever the Rongs
不管是容家也好
and the Hashimotos have,
桥本家也罢
in the end,
最后
they'll all belong to our children, no?
不都得给我的儿女吗
I'm not the shortsighted and selfish type.
我也不是那短视自私的人
I can see the big picture.
眼前不会只有那一亩三分地
Very well.
好
This is
桥本小姐真是给了我
a complete surprise.
一个意外的惊喜啊
I'm glad
我是真没想到
Jiashang has met you.
嘉上会认识你这样的女孩子
The problem is
不过
how can you make sure
你就那么有信心
Taiji will beat Taichi to the succession?
你弟弟可以取代你哥吗
I heard Taichi is getting much better.
我可是听说你大哥好点了
He's living on borrowed time.
不过是回光返照罢了
As you know,
容伯伯应该知道
he's too sick.
我大哥重病在身
He can't go out very often,
须得少出门
or be exhausted
少活动
or stressed.
更要少受刺激
Any carelessness
若是稍有不注意
and he has a relapse outside,
在外发病
that can be fatal.
就很难抢救回来
Have some tea.
喝茶
Miss Hashimoto,
桥本小姐
it's late.
时候不早啦
My driver will take you back.
我派人送你
Goodbye, Mr. Rong.
那晚辈就先告辞了
I expect to hear from you soon.
在家静候伯父佳音
Wait.
等等
He's mine!
我会得到他的
Let's go.
开车
Father.
爹
All done?
都办好了
Yes.
是啊
And the Fengs?
冯家呢
They signed it, too.
都签了合同了
Without making a scene?
居然没有闹啊
Feng Shixun did,
冯世勋闹了一场
but Feng Shizhen put her name on it.
冯世真签了合同
There was nothing else he could do.
他也无话可说
They aren't too stupid.
看来他们还挺识相的
You did well.
你都办好了
It's over now.
我就不多言了
Look at this.
你看看这个吧
What is it?
这是什么
Just now,
刚才
Hashimoto Shiori came
桥本诗织来了
with this photo.
带着这张照片
She said a lot
还说了好多话
but it was all about one thing.
不过就一个意思
Break off your engagement to Du Lanxin
让我们和杜家退婚
and marry her.
娶她
She'd give us
她会带着
the Hashimotos' property
和金麒麟
and the Gold Kylin.
嫁过来
And she wanted her elder brother dead.
她还让我帮助她除掉她大哥
I was shocked
真没看出来啊
that a young girl like her
一个小姑娘
was so wildly ambitious.
野心不小
Father,
爹
what are you going to do?
那你打算怎么办
Are you going to help her?
准备答应她吗
Taichi is Hashimoto Shozo's lawful heir.
那可是桥本正三的嫡长子啊
No way would I listen to her
我怎么会
and get on the Hashimotos' bad side.
得罪整个桥本家族
Given that
至于婚事
she's a Japanese and a concubine's daughter
一个出身卑微的日本人的庶女
of humble birth but evil mind
小小年纪 心机深沉
who'd murder her family
为了谋权夺利
for her own gain,
不惜残害自己的家人
she can be
这样的人
a useful pawn,
合作利用尚可
but never
做家人
a family member.
万万不可
In this case,
既然如此
let's cancel the engagement first.
不如先和杜家退婚吧
Du Lanxin is promiscuous
杜兰馨这个水性杨花的女人
and brings it on herself.
自己做的丑事
We have every right
我们和她退婚
to get rid of her.
理所应当
But that can wait.
不过这事
What's your plan?
您到底打算如何处置
The Central China Antique Charity Auction,
下个月
held every five years,
会举办五年一届的
will open in the city museum next month.
华中古玩慈善拍卖会
Our family is invited.
咱们家全家都去
Take Du Lanxin with you.
你带上杜兰馨
(Auction Invitation) Bring the invitations to the Hashimotos.
把这几张帖子给桥本家送去
Miss Hashimoto
也算是
is going to need one.
我给桥本小姐行个方便吧